# **Uthen Thianprateep**

Mobile: +6686 5630778

Email: <u>ut5001@gmail.com</u>

https://github.com/ut5001

https://www.linkedin.com/in/uthen-

thianprateep-18867931/



#### CAREER SUMMARY

IT System administration with more than 20 years of professional experience with several different platforms such as Windows and Linux. Have a wide range of technical skills in systems installation, configuration, upgrading and maintenance. Dynamic extensive experience with security, database management and technical troubleshooting. Committed and passionate with technology and network administration and effective project management skills.

Update, Up-Skill and Re-Skill about New Technology and apply to business.

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Looking for a new challenging position in IT and Network security for corporations to support a large scale of users and apply new technogy to business .

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Expert knowledge of operation systems such as Mac OS, Windows, and Linux.
- Experience in Ciscoworks, DHCP, SNMP, SQL, C++, and Python.
- Networking systems such as LAN, WAN.
- Data warehouse and ETL concept.
- Knowledge about R, Python, PySpark, and shell script.
- Coding application with Hadoop components HDFS, Hive, Sqoop, Flue, etc,
- DevOps, Cloud Technology

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Artificial Intelligence Association of Thailand: AI Engineer. (APR 2023 - JUN 2023)

- Frontier Research Project. : Apply ML for Nuclear Fusion Reactor.
- Frontier Research Project.: Apply ML for Synchrotron Radiation Techniques and Accelerator Machine

Super AI Engineer Season 3 (OCT 2022 - MAR 2023)

- Learn Python Programming and LIBRARIES.: TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, PyTorch Lightning, Scikit-Learn, LightGBM, SciPy, Transformers, Geopandas, PyCaret, OpenCV, Pillow, DEAP
- Learn AI algorithm for apply Mini-Hackathon exam and present result to board .
- Team working with the members of Hackathon team for result of Mini-Hackathon.
- Used Super computer (Lanta: Mange OS Linux) for apply Mini-Hackathon exam, (apply Fast API).
- Used Huawei Cloud for apply API and trans AI model .

#### **ACHIEVEMENT**

- 1st RUNNER UP Hackathon Unsupervise Image search in Logos
- 2nd RUNNER UP Hackathon Mobile Robot with Reinforcement Learning
- 2nd RUNNER UP Hackathon CMSK Chatbot

  Extractive Question Answering
- 2nd RUNNER UP Hackathon Ultra-wide (UWB) Pose Prediction
- Winner Hackathon: Hackathon Frontiers

# **Data Master (DEC 2022 - MAR 2023)**

- Need to use information efficiently
- Can use Google Cloud Platform (GCP) and basic use of Google BigQuery.
- Understand the Google BigQuery interface and try running queries.
- Able to use basic SQL commands and commonly used functions to perform operations and manipulate complex data.
- Learn Window function and Analytics function.

### IBM Solutions: IT System Administrator.

(Aug 2013 – Aug 2021)

#### Key responsibilities:

- Responsible for receiving and transmitting the pure and reliable message, tracking vehicles and equipment, and recording other important information applied by ITIL.
- IT system administrator: (windows base).
- Continuously drive to improve processes for improved performance.
- Developed strategy and created metrics to measure the effectiveness of the strategy.
- Performed application monitoring and performance tuning.
- Performed custom application changes in development, validation or equivalent testing environment and production environments.
- Performed operation system software updates, upgrades and patches fix VA report.
- Manage others through convenience rather than use direct authority.

Performed administration activities such as setting user accounts, roles, access and privileges.

#### **ACHIEVEMENT**

- Achieved monthly SLA target agreed between client and IBM team.
- Customer satisfaction with the higher level.

# ATOS (Thailand): IT System administration (Mail Support)

(Apr 2011 - Jul 2013)

#### Key responsibilities:

- Continuously drive to improve processes for improved performance.
- Performed administration activities such as setting user accounts, roles, access and privileges, support incident, service request from customers and generating monthly incident report for supervisor.

### **Terabyte Net Solution: IT System administrator outsourcing**

(Jan 2007 - Mar 2011)

### Key responsibilities:

- Continuously drive to improve processes for improved performance.
- Performed administration activities such as setting user accounts, roles access, and privileges, support incident, service request from customer.
- IT implementer.
- Visit customer site, implement HP server product, support onsite for incident.

### **True Corp: Engineer / IT implementer**

(Feb 2003 - Dec 2006)

#### Key responsibilities:

- Designed and Configured company products.
- Support IT Production for SMB customers based on company products.
- IT System administrator outsourcing.
- Continuously drive to improve processes for improved performance.
- Performed administration activities such as setting user accounts, roles, access, and privileges, support incident, service request from customer.

# **SVOA Co., LTD**

(May 2001 - Jan 2003)

# **Key responsibilities:**

 Provide IT solutions to customer implement and support after implementation for government customer, enterprise business.

### **CSCI**; Support Engineer

(Jan 2001 - Apr 2001)

### **Key responsibilities:**

• Installed and support IT production (Desktop, notebook, Printer, etc)

# Elec & Eltec Thailand; Engineer

(Jan 2000 – Dec 2000)

### **Key responsibilities:**

• Maintenance Engineer, Managed & protection planning for machine on production line

### **EDUCATION**

**Kasetsart University** 

Bachelor of Engineering, Major: Electrical (1995 - 1999)

Super AI (OCT 2022 - Present day)

### **REFEREES**

will provide upon request.